Guide to the Arlen Specter Senatorial Papers, Group 6. Public Relations and Media Files, 1972-2010 TJU.2010.01.06
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Arlen Specter Senatorial Papers, Group 6. Public Relations and Media Files
1972-2010
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Specter, Arlen
TJU.2010.01.06
196.67 Linear Feet
The Arlen Specter Senatorial Papers, Group 6. Public Relations and Media Files document the public relations and outreach functions of Senator Specter's office. These files include video recordings of public and Senate appearances, along with interview transcripts, newsclips, press releases, publication drafts, and speeches.
Custodial History
Material was transferred to the care of Philadelphia University in 2010-2011 from the Federal Records Storage Facility in Suitland, Maryland, as well as the Senator's Washington, D.C. and Pennsylvania offices. The physical material was transferred to the University of Pittsburgh in 2014, with the exception of selected photographic and memorabilia items that remain at the Arlen Specter Center's Roxboro House for display. In 2016, Philadelphia University merged with Thomas Jefferson University, and is now known as Thomas Jefferson University- East Falls campus.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Arlen Specter to Philadelphia University in 2010. Philadelphia University and the University of Pittsburgh entered into a partnership to jointly manage the collection in 2013.
Biography
Born in Wichita, Kansas, on February 12, 1930, Arlen Specter came to Pennsylvania to attend the University of Pennsylvania. He married Joan Levy in 1953, and graduated from Yale Law School in 1956. He became assistant district attorney in Philadelphia in 1959. In 1962, Specter was recommended to serve on the Warren Commission, assembled to investigate the assassination of President John F. Kennedy. As part of the Commission, he was responsible for co-authoring the proposal of the "single bullet theory," determining that one bullet struck both President Kennedy and Texas Governor John Connally. Specter ran for Philadelphia district attorney in 1965, switching his Party membership to Republican in order to unseat the incumbent Democrat. He was successful, and served as district attorney from 1966 to 1974.
After an initial failed run for Senator and then for Governor of Pennsylvania, Specter was elected to the U.S. Senate in 1980. He would stay in this position from 1981 to 2011, making him the longest-tenured senator in Pennsylvania's history. During this time, he was a member of a number of Committees: Judiciary (1981-2011; Chair, 2007-2007), Appropriations (1981-2011), Veterans Affairs (1981-2011; Chair, 1997-2001 and 2003-2005), Select Intelligence (1985-1991; 1995-1997; Chair, 1995-1997), Special Aging (1991-1995; 2007-2011), Governmental Affairs (1997-2001; 2003-2005), and Environment and Public Works (2001-2003; 2009-2011).
Though elected as a Republican, Specter was a moderate on many issues, including healthcare reform, immigration, and abortion. He would often cross party lines, such as in voting against the confirmation of President Ronald Reagan's nominee Judge Robert Bork to the Supreme Court in 1987. Specter would again come into the spotlight during a Supreme Court nomination process in 1991, for his cross-examination of Professor Anita Hill regarding her allegations against nominee Clarence Thomas. In 1999, he would vote against the charges brought against President Bill Clinton, giving an answer of "not proven" to reflect his belief that Clinton had not received a fair trial.
As Senator, Specter championed a number of causes and influenced many legislative areas. He was frequently a member of Congressional Delegation trips, particularly to the Middle East, where he would speak out on the cause of freedom from religious persecution and the importance of strong diplomatic relations. He was also a proponent of funding for medical research, including the use of stem cells. He advocated for strict crime laws, particularly for career criminals. His focus on benefitting Pennsylvania could be seen through the pursuit of grant funding opportunities and his attempt to prevent the closure of the Philadelphia Naval Shipyard in the 1990s.
With the worsening of Congressional partisanship in the late 2000s, Specter found himself frequently voting with his Democratic peers. After being one of only three handful of Republicans to vote for the American Recovery and Reinvestment Act in 2009, Specter found himself increasingly marginalized within his party. In April 2009, he returned to the Democratic Party, helping to ensure the passage of the Affordable Care Act. Seeking re-election in 2010, he was defeated in the Democratic primary by Joe Sestak.
Specter's 30-year tenure in the Senate concluded in January 2011. After leaving the Senate, he partnered with Philadelphia University (now Jefferson-East Falls) to establish the Arlen Specter Center for Public Service. In the fall of 2012, Specter, who had previously beaten Hodgkin's lymphoma in 2005 while serving as Chair of the Judiciary Committee, was diagnosed with cancer. He died on October 14, 2012, aged 82.
Scope and Content Notes
The Arlen Specter Senatorial Papers, Group 6. Public Relations and Media Files comprises 158 boxes of material documenting the public relations and outreach functions of Senator Specter's office. This material includes interviews, speeches, video recordings of public and Senate appearances. There are also files relating to Specter's published works, including two of his autobiographies. Two sections of this group have been digitzed and are available online: Press Releases, and Speeches. The group contains interview transcripts, VHS tapes, DVDs, newsclips, press releases, memos, correspondence, drafts, op-eds, and speeches.
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Arrangement
Group 6 is arranged into six series reflecting the public relations and outreach functions of Senator Specter's office:
Series I. Interviews, 1981-2002
Series II. Media Appearances, 1972-2010
Series III. Newsclips, 1980-2010
Series IV. Press Office, 1981-2005
Series V. Publications, 1982-2008
Series VI. Speeches, 1981-1999
Related Materials
Arlen Specter Senatorial Papers, Group 1. Pre-Senatorial Career Files, 1953-1980, TJU.2010.01.01
Arlen Specter Senatorial Papers, Group 2. Legislative Files, 1965-2011, TJU.2010.01.02
Arlen Specter Senatorial Papers, Group 3. Personal, Political and Official Files, 1944-2010, TJU.2010.01.03
Arlen Specter Senatorial Papers, Group 4. Office Administration Files, 1962-2010, TJU.2010.01.04
Arlen Specter Senatorial Papers, Group 5. Constituent Services Files, 1976-2007, TJU.2010.01.05
Arlen Specter Senatorial Papers, Group 7. Campaign Files, 1976-2004, TJU.2010.01.07
Arlen Specter Senatorial Papers, Group 8. Awards and Memorabilia, 1957-2010, TJU.2010.01.08
Arlen Specter Senatorial Papers, Group 9. Photographs, 1930-2010, TJU.2010.01.09
Arlen Specter Senatorial Papers, Group 10. Electronic Records, 1980-2010, TJU.2010.01.10
Politicians; Legislators; Legislation; Pennsylvania; Pennsylvania -- Politics and government; Government; Video recordings; Clippings (Information artifacts); Speeches; Press releases; United States. Congress; United States. Congress. Senate; Specter, Arlen
- Interviews, 1981-2002; I.
  Scope and Content Notes
  The Interviews series includes transcripts of various interviews given by Senator Specter throughout his career. The files are arranged chronologically.
  - Television interviews, 1981-1984 (Box 1080, Folder 1)
  - Sportsbeat radio interview, 1984 (Box 1080, Folder 2)
  - Television interviews, 1985-1988 (Box 1080, Folder 3)
  - Television interviews, 1989-1990 (Box 1080, Folder 4)
  - Interview transcripts, 1991 (Box 1080, Folder 5)
  - News conferences, 1991 (Box 1080, Folder 6)
  - Interview transcripts, 1992 (Box 1080, Folder 7)
  - Interview transcripts, 1993 (Box 1080, Folder 8)
  - Interview transcripts, 1994 (Box 1080, Folder 9)
  - Radio news conferences, 1994-1995 (Box 1080, Folder 10)
  - Interview transcripts, January-April 1995 (Box 1080, Folder 11)
  - Interview transcripts, May-November 1995 (Box 1080, Folder 12)
  - Radio news conferences, 1996 (Box 1080, Folder 13)
  - Interview transcripts, January-July 1996 (Box 1080, Folder 14)
  - Interview transcripts, August-December 1996 (Box 1080, Folder 15)
  - Phi Beta Kappa Key Reporter interview, 1996-1997 (Box 1080, Folder 16)
  - Interview transcripts, January-March 1997 (Box 1080, Folder 17)
  - Interview transcripts, April-June 1997 (Box 1080, Folder 18)
  - Interview transcripts, July-September 1997 (Box 1080, Folder 19)
  - Interview transcripts, September-October 1997 (Box 1080, Folder 20)
  - Interview transcripts, January-March 1998 (Box 1080, Folder 21)
  - Interview transcripts, May-August 1998 (Box 1080, Folder 22)
  - Interview transcripts, 2002 (Box 1080, Folder 23)
- Media Appearances, 1972-2010; II.
  The Media Appearances series inlcudes video and audio recordings of public and Senate appearances by Senator Specter throughout his career. This includes recordings of public events, appearances on news programming, floor statements given in the Senate, and recordings of Senate committee hearings. This series also includes a small amount of material on Senator Specter before taking office, namely related to his failed 1978 campaign for Governor of Pennsylvania. The material is arranged chronologically.
  - District attorney spots, 1972-1974 (Box 1081, Video 1-4)
  - Brandywine Club, 1978 (Box 1081, Video 5)
  - Specter for Governor, 1978 (Box 1081, Video 6)
  - Specter for Governor: Steel, Thousands, Philadelphia, 1978 (Box 1081, Video 7)
  - Specter for Governor, TV voice tracks, 1978 (Box 1081, Video 8)
  - Republican gubernatorial spots, 1978 (Box 1081, Video 9)
  - Arlen Specter #1, undated (Box 1081, Video 10)
  - Arlen Specter #3, undated (Box 1081, Video 11)
  - Campaign spots, undated (Box 1081, Video 12)
  - Gun control, undated (Box 1081, Video 13)
  - Italian market, undated (Box 1081, Video 14)
  - Joan, undated (Box 1081, Video 15)
  - Specter reels, undated (Box 1081, Video 16-19)
  - WTAE, Joan and Arlen interview, undated (Box 1081, Video 20)
  - Specter for Governor, 1978 (Box 1082, Video 1-4)
  - Close Up Juvenile Justice: A Case of Special Needs, April 29, 1981 (Box 1083, Video 1)
  - Close Up, April 29, 1981 (Box 1083, Video 2)
  - NBC Nightly News and CBS Evening News: Judiciary Committee Hearings on Insanity Plea, June 24, 1982 (Box 1083, Video 3)
  - NBC and ABC Nightly News, June 24, 1982 (Box 1083, Video 4)
  - WPXI-TV: Arlen Specter on Squash with CBF, April 14, 1983 (Box 1083, Video 5)
  - WPVI-TV: People to People, April 30, 1983 (Box 1083, Video 6)
  - WPVI-TV: People to People, April 30, 1983 (Box 1083, Video 7)
  - Local Newsclips: Veterans' Affairs, Child Pornography, Abduction, Prison Reform, May 15, 1983 (Box 1083, Video 8)
  - Sunday World News: The Specters, May 29, 1983 (Box 1083, Video 9)
  - WQED: The People's Business, August 12, 1983 (Box 1083, Video 10)
  - Channel 11 Fayette County: Senator Specter and Doctor Esquerra, December 29, 1983 (Box 1083, Video 11)
  - NBC Art Kent: Missing Children, February 1, 1984 (Box 1083, Video 12)
  - CBS, Philadelphia Navy Yard, February 6, 1984 (Box 1083, Video 13)
  - Channel 22 (WDAU) Coverage of Senator Specter's Trip to Pittsburgh, February 10, 1984 (Box 1083, Video 14)
  - NBC, El Salvador, April 1, 1984 (Box 1083, Video 15)
  - WDAU/WBRE, May 7, 1984 (Box 1083, Video 16)
  - Senator Specter calls for review of DC criminal justice system, June 22, 1984 (Box 1083, Video 17)
  - Scranton Drunk Driving, June 26, 1984 (Box 1083, Video 18)
  - WNEP, WDAU: Blood Alcohol Level Town Meeting, June 26, 1984 (Box 1083, Video 19)
  - ABC, Good Morning America, Child porn, September 12, 1984 (Box 1083, Video 20)
  - Capitol News Conference, October 10, 1984 (Box 1083, Video 21)
  - Channel 21 (Harrisburg): Harrisburg Prison Tour, October 15, 1984 (Box 1083, Video 22)
  - Harrisburg, York, Philadelphia, Harrisburg/York, October 15, 1984; October 23, 1984; December 4, 1984; December 14, 1984 (Box 1083, Video 23)
  - ABC News, TV violence, October 26, 1984 (Box 1083, Video 24)
  - WDAU/WBRE: Arlen Specter Trip to Wilkes-Barre/Scranton, December 10, 1984 (Box 1083, Video 25)
  - ABC Sports Beat: Philadelphia Eagles Wrap-Up, December 15, 1984 (Box 1083, Video 26)
  - Nightline, Philadelphia Eagles and Senator Specter, December 15, 1984 (Box 1084, Video 1)
  - ABC, McNeil Leher NewsHour, Interview, December 31, 1984 (Box 1084, Video 2)
  - Evening News Segments from Various Stations, 1984 (Box 1084, Video 3)
  - KYW-TV: Senators Specter and Heinz Announce Contract for Navy Yard, 1984 (Box 1084, Video 4)
  - NBC-TV (Local): Senator Specter Speaks for Increased Air Traffic at Harrisburg Airport, 1984 (Box 1084, Video 5)
  - KDKA-TV, WPXI-TV, WBRE-TV, WDAU-TV: Subway, Prison, 1984 (Box 1084, Video 6)
  - WDAU: Drunk Driving, 1981-1984 (Box 1084, Video 7)
  - Specter-Heinz Show: Senators Specter and Heinz, January 19, 1985 (Box 1084, Video 8)
  - Capitol News Conference Senators Specter and Heinz, January 23, 1985 (Box 1084, Video 9)
  - ABC: Holocaust, January 29, 1985 (Box 1084, Video 10)
  - ABC and CBS: Drug Trafficking - Senators Specter and D'Amato, February 28, 1985 (Box 1084, Video 11)
  - Local News Stories: Senator Specter, March 1, 1985 (Box 1084, Video 12)
  - WSEE Senators: Specter, March 14, 1985 (Box 1084, Video 13)
  - People Are Talking: Joan Specter, Smoking Ban by City Council, March 18, 1985 (Box 1084, Video 14)
  - CBS, NBC, ABC, Interviews, March 19, 1985 (Box 1084, Video 15)
  - KYW Channel 3: Bush, Senator Specter at Philadelphia Fundraiser, March 20, 1985 (Box 1084, Video 16)
  - Face the Nation: Senator Specter's Reaction to Reagan's Visit to Bitburg, April 28, 1985 (Box 1084, Video 17)
  - Face the Nation, April 29, 1985 (Box 1084, Video 18)
  - WJAC: Senator Specter, May 23, 1985 (Box 1084, Video 19)
  - Specter-Heinz Show: Senators Specter and Heinz, May 23, 1985 (Box 1084, Video 20)
  - Committee on the Judiciary Confirmation Hearing of William Bradford Reynolds, June 4, 1985 (Box 1084, Video 21)
  - Senator Specter, June 13, 1985 (Box 1084, Video 22)
  - Capitol News Conference: Senator Specter, June 20, 1985 (Box 1084, Video 23)
  - C-TV Washington, D.C.: Senator Specter on D.C. Jails, July 24, 1985 (Box 1084, Video 24)
  - WQLN-Erie: Open House with Senator Specter, August 14, 1985 (Box 1084, Video 25)
  - Pittsburgh Voter's Issues, October 30, 1985 (Box 1084, Video 26)
  - Pittsburgh Voter's Issues, October 30, 1985 (Box 1085, Video 1)
  - Channel 3: Senator Specter, November 15, 1985 (Box 1085, Video 2)
  - Channel 6: Senator Specter, November 15, 1985 (Box 1085, Video 3)
  - Channel 10: Senator Specter, November 15, 1985 (Box 1085, Video 4)
  - Capitol News Conference: Senator Specter, November 22, 1985 (Box 1085, Video 5)
  - Channel 10: Senator Specter, November 26, 1985 (Box 1085, Video 6)
  - State of Pennsylvania Taxation, December 5, 1985 (Box 1085, Video 7)
  - CBS and ABC News Spot Senator Specter, December 9, 1985 (Box 1085, Video 8)
  - CBS and ABC News, December 9, 1985 (Box 1085, Video 9)
  - Specter and Heinz Show: Senators Specter and Heinz, December 11, 1985 (Box 1085, Video 10)
  - Channel 6: Senator Specter, December 12, 1985 (Box 1085, Video 11)
  - Watch on Washington: Joan Specter Discusses the Role of Congressional Wives, December, 1985 (Box 1085, Video 12)
  - Channel 3: Interview with Senator Specter, January 1, 1986 (Box 1085, Video 13)
  - Channel 6: Interview with Senator Specter, January 4-5, 1986 (Box 1085, Video 14)
  - CBS Nightwatch, January 13, 1986 (Box 1085, Video 15)
  - CBS Nightwatch Debate with Dr. Robert Taylor, January 13, 1986 (Box 1085, Video 16)
  - CBS Nightwatch Debate with Senator Specter and William Taylor, January 13, 1986 (Box 1085, Video 17)
  - KDKA and WTAE: Senator Specter at Westinghouse Research and Development Center, January 14, 1986 (Box 1085, Video 18)
  - ABC, NBC: Nicaragua Policy, March 13, 1986 (Box 1085, Video 19)
  - Pittsburgh Stations: Flood of Pittsburgh Area, May 5, 1986 to June 5, 1986 (Box 1085, Video 20)
  - The Garth Group, Specter 86 campaign spots, May 28, 1986 (Box 1085, Video 21)
  - Channel 6 Action News, Primary debate with Bob Edgar and Don Bailey, May 1986 (Box 1085, Video 22)
  - Channel 2 and 4 Pittsburgh Report on Flooding with Senator Specter, June 2 and 11, 1986 (Box 1085, Video 23)
  - C-SPAN Interview with Senator Specter, June 3, 1986 (Box 1085, Video 24)
  - Floor Statement, June 3 and 4, 1986 (Box 1085, Video 25)
  - Floor Statement, June 3, 1986 (Box 1085, Video 26)
  - "Call Senator Specter" Promo, June 6, 1986 (Box 1085, Video 27)
  - CBS Sunday Morning Interview with Senator Specter, June 8, 1986 (Box 1085, Video 28)
  - C-SPAN Interview with Arlen Specter, June 12, 1986 (Box 1085, Video 29)
  - Floor Statement, June 17 and 23, 1986 (Box 1085, Video 30)
  - C-SPAN Interview with Senator Specter, June 20, 1986 (Box 1085, Video 31)
  - Capitol News Conference: Senators Specter and Heinz on Tax Reform, June 27, 1986 (Box 1086, Video 1)
  - CNN Business Morning Interview with Senator Specter, August 8, 1986 (Box 1086, Video 2)
  - Channel 3: Senator Specter and Local News, August 11, 1986 (Box 1086, Video 3)
  - Channel 10: Local News and Senator Specter, August 11, 1986 (Box 1086, Video 4)
  - Channel 10 Philly, Tax reform plan segment, August 1986 (Box 1086, Video 5)
  - Channel 6: Senator Specter and Local News, September 4, 1986 (Box 1086, Video 6)
  - Channel 6 and 29: Senator Specter and Local News, September 4, 1986 (Box 1086, Video 7)
  - Channel 3 and 29: Senator Specter and Local News, September 5, 1986 (Box 1086, Video 8)
  - Channel 29: Senator Specter and Local News, September 8, 1986 (Box 1086, Video 9)
  - Channel 6: Senator Specter and Local News, September 7, 1986 (Box 1086, Video 10)
  - Local News: Specter, September 16, 1986 (Box 1086, Video 11)
  - Channel 38 Scranton Northeast Newsbeat: Congressman Edgar on Show, October 12, 1986 (Box 1086, Video 12)
  - KDKA-TV 2: Tax Reform, Coal Strike, Campaign, 1986 (Box 1086, Video 13)
  - WTAE-TV: Senator Specter, Election Night, November 4, 1986 (Box 1086, Video 14)
  - WPXI-TV: Senator Specter, Election Night, November 4, 1986 (Box 1086, Video 15)
  - WPVI Channel 6: Issues and Answers, November 6, 1986 (Box 1086, Video 16)
  - WPVI Channel 6: Aid to the Contras as a Federal Violation, November 24, 1986 (Box 1086, Video 17)
  - WPVI Channel 6: Iran-Contra Interview with Senator Specter, November 25, 1986 (Box 1086, Video 18)
  - CBS Evening News: Interview with Senator Specter About Iran-Contra, December 8, 1986 (Box 1086, Video 19)
  - WTAE-TV: Senator Specter Interview, December 19, 1986 (Box 1086, Video 20)
  - Campaign Opponent, Two Edgar Spots, 1986 (Box 1086, Video 21)
  - Edgar Post-Primary Spots (Campaign), 1986 (Box 1086, Video 22)
  - Floor Statement: Busing, Geneva Peace, 1986 (Box 1086, Video 23-24)
  - The Garth Group Campaign Spots for Senator Specter, 1986 (Box 1086, Video 25)
  - "Subway" KDKA-2 and WPXI-11 Washington Hotline; Washington Hotline; Washington Hotline; Politically Incorrect, 1986 (Box 1086, Video 26)
  - Via Satellite Senator Specter/Edgar Debate, 1986 (Box 1086, Video 27)
  - Floor Statement: Iran-Contra, January 6, 1987 (Box 1086, Video 28)
  - ABC: Good Morning America, January 16, 1987 (Box 1086, Video 29-30)
  - WPHL Productions: Profile Smith/Specter, January 29, 1987 (Box 1086, Video 31)
  - WITF: State of Pennsylvania CONRAIL, January 30, 1987 (Box 1086, Video 32)
  - The State of Pennsylvania WITF "Conrail", January 30, 1987 (Box 1086, Video 33)
  - Media and Secrecy Seminars: In the Face of Terrorism: Incident in the Mediterranean Part 1; US Capitol News Conference: with Wafford; Washington Hotline with Sen. Rudman, January, 1987 (Box 1086, Video 34)
  - Media & Society Seminars IN THE FACE OF TERRORISM: Incident in the Mediterranean Part I, January, 1987 (Box 1087, Video 1)
  - State of Pennsylvania, February 26, 1987 (Box 1087, Video 2)
  - ABC, NBC, CBS: Webster Nomination Questions Regarding North Memorandum, February 28, 1987 (Box 1087, Video 3)
  - CBS Arms Talks TV Show with Heinz, March 4, 1987 (Box 1087, Video 4)
  - Floor Statement: Resolution for the Immunity for North, March 11, 1987 (Box 1087, Video 5)
  - Channel 21 WHP-TV: Mechanicsville Tour of Naval Ships Parts Control, March 16, 1987 (Box 1087, Video 6)
  - Public Hearing on Budget in Erie, March 23, 1987 (Box 1087, Video 7)
  - WSEE, WICU, WJET: Local News, March 23, 1987 (Box 1087, Video 8)
  - WGAL-TV Lancaster News, March 25, 1987 (Box 1087, Video 9)
  - Specter-Heinz Show, March 25, 1987 (Box 1087, Video 10)
  - National News Webster Hearing, April 8, 1987 (Box 1087, Video 11)
  - Capitol News Conference, April 22, 1987 (Box 1087, Video 12)
  - WGAL-TV: Farm, May 18, 1987 (Box 1087, Video 13)
  - Capitol News Conference, May 20, 1987 (Box 1087, Video 14)
  - Biznet US Chamber of Commerce, May 20, 1987 (Box 1087, Video 15)
  - Sports Pros and Cons: Aired Specter vs. Alioto, June 13, 1987 (Box 1087, Video 16)
  - Specter-Heinz Show, June 25, 1987 (Box 1087, Video 17)
  - Floor Statement: Debate of Specter Trade Bill Amendment, June 25, 1987 (Box 1087, Video 18)
  - Floor Statement: Trade Bill Amendment, June 25, 1987 (Box 1087, Video 19)
  - CBS Evening News: Justice Powell Retirement, June 26, 1987 (Box 1087, Video 20)
  - CBS National News: Senator Specter's Speech, Bicentennial of Constitution, July 16, 1987 (Box 1087, Video 21)
  - Paoli Railyard, July 27, 1987 (Box 1087, Video 22)
  - TV3 PC-Paoli Railyard, July 27, 1987 (Box 1087, Video 23)
  - TV 6 PA Paoli Rail, July 27, 1987 (Box 1087, Video 24)
  - Capitol News Conference, July 29, 1987 (Box 1087, Video 25)
  - CNN Newsmaker Saturday: The Hostage Dilemma... What Should the US Do?, August 5, 1987 (Box 1087, Video 26)
  - Channel 3, 6, 10: Senator Specter Endorses Mayor Rizzo, September 2, 1987 (Box 1087, Video 27)
  - Bethlehem Steel Footage for Burns Harbor Plant, September 8, 1987 (Box 1087, Video 28)
  - Network Coverage: Judge Bork/Senator Specter, September 15, 1987 (Box 1087, Video 29)
  - ABC, CBS Nightly News: Last Day of Bork Hearings, September 18, 1987 (Box 1087, Video 30)
  - Bork Nomination Day 5, September 19, 1987 (Box 1087, Video 31)
  - Senate confirmation hearings, Specter interrogation of Judge Bork, September 19, 1987 (Box 1087, Video 32)
  - Purdue University Public Affairs Video Archives: Bork Nomination Day 5, September 19, 1987 (Box 1088, Video 1)
  - The Questioning of Judge Bork Compiled Program, C-SPAN Archives, September 19, 1987 (Box 1088, Video 2)
  - Senate Confirmation Hearings: Judge Bork's Testimony, September 19, 1987 (Box 1088, Video 3)
  - Face the Nation: Bork/Specter/DeConcini, September 20, 1987 (Box 1088, Video 4)
  - Capitol News Conference, September 22, 1987 (Box 1088, Video 5)
  - ABC Good Morning America: Bork, September 28, 1987 (Box 1088, Video 6)
  - Bork Nomination Day 5, September 1987 (Box 1088, Video 7)
  - Channel 6 Philly, Bork nomination; ABC This Week with David Brinkley, Bork, September 1987 (Box 1088, Video 8)
  - WITF Conrail; Bork Nomination Day 5, September 1987 (Box 1088, Video 9)
  - Confirmation Hearing - Bork, September 1987 (Box 1088, Video 10)
  - Constitution Bicentennial Celebration in Philadelphia – Opening Ceremony, September 1987 (Box 1088, Video 11)
  - The Questioning of Judge Bork, September 1987 (Box 1088, Video 12)
  - Senate Confirmation Hearings (Day 1) Judge Bork: Opening Statements, September 1987 (Box 1088, Video 13)
  - Senate Confirmation Hearings Day 1 Judge Bork – Opening Statements; News Packages on Senator Specter's Trip to Israel, September 1987 (Box 1088, Video 14)